<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="psalm-103">

    <title>
     <section xml:lang="ru">Псалом 103</section>
    </title>
 
    <shortdesc>The Psalm Of Introduction (103)</shortdesc>
 
    <body>
 
     <section xml:lang="ru">
          <p><div class="speaker">Чтец:</div> Bless the Lord, O my soul; O Lord my God, Thou hast been magnified exceedingly. Покрываяй водами превыспренняя Своя, полагаяй облаки на восхождение Свое, ходяй на крилу ветреню. Творяй Ангелы Своя духи и слуги Своя пламень огненный.</p>
          <p>Who establisheth the earth in the sureness thereof; it shall not be turned back forever and ever. The abyss like a garment is His mantle; upon the mountains shall the waters stand. At Thy rebuke they will flee, at the voice of Thy thunder shall they be afraid.</p>
          <p>Восходят горы и нисходят поля в место, еже основал еси им. Предел положил еси, eгоже не прейдут, ниже обратятся покрыти землю. Thou appointedst a bound that they shall not pass, neither return to cover the earth. Посылаяй источники в дебрех, посреде гор пройдут воды. Напаяют вся звери сельныя, ждут онагри в жажду свою. На тых птицы небесныя привитают, от среды камения дадят глас.</p>
          <p>Напаяяй горы от превыспренних Своих, от плода дел Твоих насытится земля. Прозябаяй траву скотом, и злак на службу человеком, извести хлеб от земли. И вино веселит сердце человека, умастити лице елеем, и хлеб сердце человека укрепит.</p>
          <p>Насытятся древа польская, кедри Ливанстии, ихже еси насадил. Тамо птицы вогнездятся, еродиево жилище предводительствует ими. Горы высокия еленем, камень прибежище заяцем.</p>
          <p>Сотворил есть луну во времена, солнце позна запад свой. Thou appointedst the darkness, and there was the night, wherein all the beasts of the forest will go abroad; young lions roaring after their prey, and seeking their food from God. Возсия солнце и собрашася и в ложах своих лягут. Изыдет человек на дело свое и на делание свое до вечера. How magnified are Thy works, O Lord! In wisdom hast Thou made them all.</p>
          <p>The earth is filled with Thy creation. Сие море великое и пространное, тамо гади, имже несть числа, животная малая с великими, тамо корабли преплавают, змий сей, eгоже создал еси ругатися eму. There go the ships; there this leviathan, whom Thou hast made to play therein. Вся к Тебе чают, дати пищу им во благо время. When Thou openest Thy hand, all things shall be filled with goodness; when Thou turnest away Thy face, they shall be troubled. Thou wilt take their spirit, and they shall cease; and unto their dust shall they return. Послеши Духа Твоего, и созиждутся, и обновиши лице земли.</p>
          <p>Let the glory of the Lord be unto the ages; the Lord will rejoice in His works. Who looketh on the earth and maketh it tremble, Who toucheth the mountains and they smoke. I will sing unto the Lord throughout my life, I will chant to my God for as long as I have my being.</p>
          <p>Да усладится Ему беседа моя, аз же возвеселюся о Господе. Да исчезнут грешницы от земли, и беззаконницы, якоже не быти им. Благослови, душе моя, Господа. Благослови, душе моя, Господа.</p>
          <p>Солнце позна запад свой. Thou appointedst the darkness, and there was the night. How magnified are Thy works, O Lord! In wisdom hast Thou made them all.</p>
     </section>
 
    </body>
 
 </topic>
