<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="great-litany">
     
     <title>
          <section xml:lang="en">Great Litany</section>
     </title>
     
     <shortdesc>Great Litany</shortdesc>
     
     <related-links>
          <linklist scope="external">
               <link href="https://antiochianprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/musiclibrary/great_litany-byzantine-2_versions.pdf">
                    <linktext>Antiochian Village / El Massih</linktext>
                    <desc>Byzantine, simple chant, Chant, Antiochian Village, Deacon John El Massih</desc>
               </link>
               <link href="https://antiochianprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/musiclibrary/matins-kazan-complete-2-the_great_litany_p7.pdf">
                    <linktext>Kazan</linktext>
                    <desc>Chant, Tone : 2, Basil Kazan</desc>
               </link>
               <link href="https://antiochianprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/musiclibrary/vespers-kazan-2-great_litany.pdf">
                    <linktext>Russian / Gelsinger</linktext>
                    <desc>Choral, Tone : Russian, Michael G.H. Gelsinger</desc>
               </link>
               <link href="https://antiochianprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/musiclibrary/01F%20The%20Great%20Litany-Finley.pdf">
                    <linktext>Finley</linktext>
                    <desc>1F, Choral, Archpriest John Finley</desc>
               </link>
               <link href="https://antiochianprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/musiclibrary/great_litany-t8_byz.pdf">
                    <linktext>Traditional</linktext>
                    <desc>Byzantine, Tone 8, Chant, Tone : 8, Traditional</desc>
               </link>
               <link href="https://antiochianprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/musiclibrary/Great_Litany-Romanian.pdf">
                    <linktext>Romanian</linktext>
                    <desc>Choral, Romanian, St. Vladimir's Seminary Press</desc>
               </link>
          </linklist>
     </related-links>
     
     <body>
          <section xml:lang="en">
               <p><div class="speaker">Deacon:</div> In peace, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p><div class="speaker">Choir:</div> Lord, have mercy. <note>(Use this response until noted below)</note></p>
               <p><div class="speaker">Deacon:</div> For the peace from above and the salvation of our souls, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For the peace of the whole world, the good estate of the holy churches of God and the union of all, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For this holy house and those who with faith, reverence and fear of God enter therein, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For our father and metropolitan, N., (our bishop, N.,) the honorable presbytery, the diaconate in Christ, all the clergy and the people, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For our country, its president (or appropriate head of state), civil authorities and armed forces, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For this city and every city and countryside and the faithful who dwell therein, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For healthful seasons, abundance of the fruits of the earth and peaceful times, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For travelers by sea, by land and by air, the sick, the suffering, the captive, and for their salvation, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>For our deliverance from all tribulation, wrath, danger and necessity, let us pray to the Lord.</p>
               <p>Help us; save us; have mercy on us; and keep us, O God, by thy grace.</p>
               <p>Calling to remembrance our all-holy, immaculate, most blessed and glorious Lady, the Theotokos and ever-virgin Mary, with all the saints, let us commend ourselves and each other and all our life unto Christ our God.</p>
               <p><div class="speaker">Choir:</div> To Thee, O Lord.</p>
               <p><div class="speaker">Priest:</div> For unto thee are due all glory, honor and worship, to the Father and to the Son and to the Holy Spirit, now and ever, and unto ages of ages.</p>
               <p><div class="speaker">Choir:</div> Amen.</p>
          </section>
     </body>

</topic>