<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<topic id="psalm-103">

    <title>
     <section xml:lang="ar">المَزمور 103</section>
    </title>
 
    <shortdesc>The Psalm Of Introduction (103)</shortdesc>
 
    <body>
 
     <section xml:lang="ar">
          <p><div class="speaker">القارئ:</div> Bless the Lord, O my soul; O Lord my God, Thou hast been magnified exceedingly. Confession and majesty hast Thou put on, Who coverest Thyself with light as with a garment, Who stretchest out the heaven as it were a curtain; Who supporteth His chambers in the waters, Who appointeth the clouds for His ascent, Who walketh upon the wings of the winds, Who maketh His angels spirits, and His ministers a flame of fire.</p>
          <p>Who establisheth the earth in the sureness thereof; it shall not be turned back forever and ever. The abyss like a garment is His mantle; upon the mountains shall the waters stand. At Thy rebuke they will flee, at the voice of Thy thunder shall they be afraid.</p>
          <p>The mountains rise up and the plains sink down, unto the place where Thou hast established them. أنتَ الذي يَسْقِي الجِبالَ مِنْ عَلاليِّهِ، مِنْ ثَمَرَةِ أعْمالِكَ تَشْبَعُ الأرضُ. He sendeth forth springs in the valleys; between the mountains will the waters run. They shall give drink to all the beasts of the field; the wild asses will wait to quench their thirst. Beside them will the birds of the heaven lodge, from the midst of the rocks will they give voice.</p>
          <p>He watereth the mountains from His chambers; the earth shall be satisfied with the fruit of Thy works. He causeth the grass to grow for the cattle, and green herb for the service of men, to bring forth bread out of the earth; and wine maketh glad the heart of man. To make his face cheerful with oil; and bread strengtheneth man’s heart.</p>
          <p>تُرْوَى أشْجارُ الغابِ، وأرْزُ لبنانَ الذي نَصَبْتَهُ. There will the sparrows make their nests; the house of the heron is chief among them. The high mountains are a refuge for the harts, and so is the rock for the hares.</p>
          <p>He hath made the moon for seasons; the sun knoweth his going down. Thou appointedst the darkness, and there was the night, wherein all the beasts of the forest will go abroad; young lions roaring after their prey, and seeking their food from God. The sun ariseth, and they are gathered together, and they lay them down in their dens. يَخْرُجُ الإنسانُ إلى عَمَلِهِ وإلى صِناعَتِهِ حتى المَساء. How magnified are Thy works, O Lord! In wisdom hast Thou made them all.</p>
          <p>قَدِ امْتَلأَتِ الأرضُ مِنْ خليقَتِكَ. هذا البَحْرُ الكَبيرُ الواسِعُ، هناكَ دَبّاباتٌ لا عَدَدَ لَهَا، حَيَواناتٌ صِغَارٌ مَعَ كِبار. هُناكَ تَجْرِي السُّفُنُ، هذا التِّنّينُ الذي خَلَقْتَهُ يَلْعَبُ فيه. وكلُّها إيّاكَ تَتَرَجَّى، لِتُعْطيَها طعامَها في حينِه، وإذا أنتَ أعْطَيْتَها جمَعَتْ. تَفْتَحُ يدَكَ فَيَمْتَلِئُ الكُلُّ خيْراً، تَصْرِفُ وجهَكَ فَيَضْطَرِبون. تَنْزِعُ أرواحَهُمْ فَيَفْنَوْنَ، وإلى تُرابِهِمْ يَرْجِعونَ. تُرْسِلُ روحَكَ فَيُخلَقُونَ، وتُجَدِّدُ وَجْهَ الأرض.</p>
          <p>لِيَكُنْ مَجْدُ الرَّبِّ إلى الدهْرِ، يَفْرَحُ الرَّبُّ بأعمالِه. الذي يَنْظُرُ إلى الأرْضِ فيَجْعَلُها تَرْتَعِدُ، ويَمَسُّ الجبالَ فتُدَخِّنُ. أُسَبِّحُ الرَّبَّ في حَيَاتِي، وأرَّتِلُ لإلهِي ما دُمْتُ مَوْجوداً.</p>
          <p>May my words be sweet unto Him; I will rejoice in the Lord. O that sinners would cease from the earth, and they that work iniquity, that they should be no more. Bless the Lord, O my soul.</p>
          <p>The sun knoweth his going down. الشَّمْسُ عَرَفَتْ غُروبَها، جَعَلَ الظُلْمَةَ فكانَ لَيْلٌ. ما أعظَمَ أعمالَكَ يا ربُّ، كلَّها بِحِكْمَةٍ صَنَعْتَ. In wisdom hast Thou made them all.</p>
     </section>
 
    </body>
 
 </topic>
